# **Danielle Frappier**

SHE | HER

I love to create beautiful web applications and user experiences. I have successfully helped organizations deploy scalable design systems, web applications and CMS driven websites that improve SEO, lead generation and online presence.

(508) 574.0944 daniellerichard1@gmail.com daniellefrappier.com

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## **Monster** — Senior Design Systems Engineer

SEPTEMBER 2021 - PRESENT

- Team lead for Randstad Brand Design System. Responsible for mentoring junior engineers, establishing code standards and best practices and making decisions on the architecture of the design system.
- Built React component library with TypeScript & Styled Components, wrote unit tests using Jest and React Testing Library and documented components in Storybook.
- Provided support for monster.com homepage built using Gatsby.

## **John Hancock** — Front End Engineer

JANUARY 2019 - SEPTEMBER 2021

- Sole developer for web applications used by Sales, Marketing and Education departments to sell, promote and onboard clients and new users
- Developed web applications using AngularJS and ReactJS/Context API.
- Responsible for adding future forward functionality to applications and maintaining code bases.
- Accountable for QA and release process for all assigned web applications.

## **Applause** — Front End Developer

NOVEMBER 2017 - JANUARY 2019

- Lead migration and development of applause.com from contentful/middleman to CraftCMS.
- Identified areas on applause.com not accessible WCAG 2.0 compliant and implemented changes to correct.
- Implemented new landing pages and emails in Marketo.

#### WHERE YOU CAN FIND ME

linkedin.com/in/daniellefrappier github.com/daniellefrappier18 codepen.io/daniellefrapp jsfiddle.net/user/daniellefrappier

#### **TECH STACK**

#### **JavaScript**

TypeScript, ReactJS/Context API, Styled Components, Jest, React Testing Library, AngularJS

#### **CMS & Static Site Generators**

Gatsby, CraftCMS, Contentful, Wordpress, ExpressionEngine, Middleman, Jekyll

#### **Build Tools**

Lerna, Yarn Workspaces, Jenkins, Spinnaker, Sonarqube, Webpack Gulp, GIT

## **Workshop Environments**

Storybook, PatternLab

#### The Other Stuff

SCSS, LESS, TWIG, Figma, Sketch, Photoshop, Illustrator

#### WHAT I DO OUTSIDE OF WORK

Surfing, Snowboarding, Knitting and Crocheting, Sci-fi movies, reading post-apocalyptic novels

## **Aetna** — *UX Designer/Developer*

SEPTEMBER 2017 - NOVEMBER 2017

Created landing page and email templates to be WCAG 2.0 compliant.

## **EH Media** — Senior Web Designer/Developer

OCTOBER 2015 - SEPTEMBER 2017

- Designed and implemented new functionality that led to engaging product offerings and generated new revenue.
- Ensured high-performance and availability of multiple WordPress sites.
- Created WordPress themes and plugins for non-technical content creators within the company to easily publish new content while adhering to company and web best practices.

## **ACIS Educational Tours** — Web Designer/Developer

MARCH 2013 - OCTOBER 2015

- Lead designer and developer for three brands: www.acis.com, www.encoretours.com, www.goplay-sports.com.
- Designed and developed landing pages and emails in Marketo, Hubspot, and ClickDimensions.
- Designed trade show booths, print materials, infographics and Ebooks.

## **MEDITECH** — Supervisor of Web Design

OCTOBER 2006 - MARCH 2013

- Promoted three times during tenure. Previous positions held were: Senior Web Designer and Graphic Designer.
- Responsible for the successful delivery and execution of web design projects for public web presence, corporate events, and customer focused web magazine with a team of 5 designers.
- Identified and led migration from home-grown CMS to Drupal which provided the company a more efficient and modern publishing platform to deliver sales, marketing and company collateral to new and existing customers.
- Designed custom sales demos for proposals above \$1 million dollars.

### **EDUCATION**

## **Framingham State University** — BA, Graphic Design

2001 - 2006

Minors in Computer Science and Communication Arts